Animation Number 1
This is as good a time as any, so I'll talk about Araragi-kun now.
（羽川(はねかわ)）
いいタイミングなので ここで少し
阿良々木(あららぎ)くんの話をしようと思う
Talk about Araragi Koyomi
Animation Number 3
Araragi Koyomi, who is
Senjougahara's boyfriend and my friend.
Animation Number 4
Actually, I knew about Araragi-kun even before spring break.
実は 私は 阿良々木くんのことを
春休み以前から知っていた
Not everything, but I did know about him.
何でもは知らないけれど
阿良々木くんのことは 知っていた
Araragi Koyomi
Animation Number 7
Animation Number 9
He was pretty famous among the students of Naoetsu High School.
阿良々木くんは
直江津(なおえつ)高校において
結構な有名人なのだ
というか ありていに言って
悪目立ちをしていた
Or to be blunt, he was very noticeable in a bad way.
May
Sat         Fri          Thu       Wed        Tue        Mon        Sun
What was he doing, playing hooky from school and being perfunctory for class and exams?
学校をサボって
授業や試験を おざなりにして
阿良々木くんが
何をしていたのかといえば
どうも 春休みやら
ゴールデンウィークやらと
It seems he was doing something like what he had done during spring break and Golden Week.
似たり寄ったりのことを
していたようだ
The activities of the Fire Sisters, Karen-chan and Tsukihi-chan, pale in comparison.
火憐(かれん)ちゃんや月火(つきひ)ちゃんの
ファイヤーシスターズの活動だって
何のことはない
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
That is a mere rehashing of Araragi-kun's junior-high days.
阿良々木くんの中学時代の
焼き直しに すぎないのだった
もっとも
中学時代の阿良々木くんと
Of course, what he did in junior high and what he's doing in high school are basically the same.
高校時代の阿良々木くんとでは
Barely legal extracurricular activities
Animation Number 23
やっていることは同じでも
He fought the law
Animation Number 25
However, it seems there's a big difference in his motivations.
そのモチベーションには
大きな差異が あったことは
I'm pretty impressed he lived
to become a high-schooler
Animation Number 25
どうやら事実のようだ
He refuses to discuss what happened, even more than the events of spring break.
何があったのか…
その点については
春休み以上に
かたくなに語りたがらないけれど
But it seems there was a mental turning point during his first year of high school.
高校１年生のころに
何らかの精神的な転機が
あったらしい
彼いわく 落ちこぼれる原因
とでもいうのか
A cause for his "delinquencies" as he would put it.
それに
However, change or no change, Araragi-kun is Araragi-kun.
変わろうが 変わるまいが
阿良々木くんは
阿良々木くんなわけで
出会ったころはクールだった
阿良々木くんが
Naoetsu High School
He was composed when I met him, and though he's completely different now, he's still him.
今となっては
変わり果てたと言っても
それでも 彼は彼であり
そして 今日も今日とて
何やら動いているようで
And today, like any day, he's on the move for some reason.
Ever since who-knows-when, I've been in love with such a person.
私は そんな彼を いつからか
好きになってしまったのだ
Exactly when did it start?
それが いつからなのかは
My reminiscences
Animation Number 42
I'll talk about that a little bit later.
もう少し あとで話そう
Tsubasa Tiger          Part Two
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 67
Oh? We skipped another chapter? What's with that?
（羽川）
ん？　章ナンバーが
また１つ飛んでいる？
Animation Number 67
どういうことだ？
Hanekawa
Not even Araragi
Animation Number 73
could keep the sight
of this sleeping face
Animation Number 73
all to himself just yet.
Oh, good morning, Hanekawa-san.
（戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)）
あら
おはよう 羽川さん
Good morning, Senjougahara-san.
（羽川）
おはよう 戦場ヶ原さん
Though I think it's past the time to say that.
（戦場ヶ原）といっても
もう そんな時間じゃ
ないでしょうけれど
Right. It's not that time of day anymore.
（羽川）
そうだね
そんな時間じゃないね
What time is it?
（戦場ヶ原）今 何時？
（羽川）えっと…
Well, 1:30...
１時半
AM or PM?
（戦場ヶ原）午前？　午後？
PM of course.
午後に決まってるじゃない
Flashbacks follow
Animation Number 80
After that
Senjougahara-san and I really took a shower together after that conversation.
（羽川）
あれから 本当に
戦場ヶ原さんと私は
一緒にシャワーを浴びたのだった
Hot
Senjougahara-san is the type of person who creates strong walls in her heart.
戦場ヶ原さんも 心に強固な壁を
作っていたタイプの人間だ
There's no mistake her former self, nicknamed "well-to-do girl,"
間違っても “深窓の令嬢”と
呼ばれていたころの彼女なら
would never have let me stay the night or taken a shower with me.
私を家に泊めてくれたり
一緒にシャワーを浴びたりなんて
しなかっただろうし
Even before that, she would never have run around the city all night looking for me.
それ以前に ひと晩中 私を捜して
町じゅうを駆け回ったりなんて
しなかっただろう
Thinking of the sheer weight of everything she's overcome recently,
彼女が この数か月で
乗り越えてきた—
いろんなものの重さを思うと
I feel miserable about myself, because in the end
同じように
いろんな経験をしながらも
結局のところ 何ひとつ
乗り越えていない自分が
I haven't overcome a thing despite having similar experiences.
情けなくもなってしまう
That's right. I have not overcome one thing.
そうだ　私は何ひとつ
乗り越えていない
Despite the commotion during Golden Week and the day before the arts festival,
ゴールデンウィークの騒動をへても
文化祭前日の あの日をへても
I have not matured. I have not changed.
成長してない　変わっていない
That's why I envied Senjougahara-san so and loved her so.
だから 戦場ヶ原さんが
とても羨ましくて
そして とても好きで
嫌いになれないんだと思った
I couldn't bring myself to hate her.
I honestly thought that.
素直に思ったのだった
After that
Animation Number 109
Senjougahara and I had half an hour of fun
in the shower, then, feeling refreshed,
Animation Number 109
we went to the dressing room.
I'm sure you feel apprehensive about wearing my lingerie,
（戦場ヶ原）
さすがに 私の下着を
身に着けるというのは
抵抗があるでしょうけれど
羽川さん パジャマくらいは
借りてちょうだいよ
but at least borrow my pajamas.
Since you probably bought those sweats that are as gentle as a stupa at a discount store,
あの 恐らくは 何らかの
ディスカウントショップで
買ったであろう—
卒塔婆(そとば)が卒倒しそうなデザインの
スウェットは
なんだったら
私がゴミに出しておくから
I'll go ahead and throw them out.
あれ ダメ？
That outfit's no good?
Awful.
（戦場ヶ原）ひどい
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Ionized
Hanekawa-san, you've been growing your hair out since you cut it after the arts festival?
（戦場ヶ原）羽川さん
文化祭のあとに髪を切ってから
また伸ばしているわよね
（羽川）ん？　うん まあ
I guess. I haven't gone to a hair salon since then.
あれから まだ
美容院には行ってないかな
Will you grow it out again?
（戦場ヶ原）また長くするの？
Not sure. I realized for the first time after cutting my hair
う〜ん どうだろ？
短くして初めて気付いたけど
意外と ロングのほうが
that long hair is surprisingly less of a hassle to maintain.
手入れの手間が
かからなかったりするんだよね
Ionized
Maybe that's not too far-fetched a thought.
そういうところは
なきにしもあらずかも
I have another futon that my father uses, but I don't know,
（戦場ヶ原）
もう１組 お父さんの分の
布団があるんだけれど
どうかしらね
I'm uneasy letting a high-school girl sleep in the futon a forty-something old man usually sleeps in.
40過ぎの中年のおじさんが
ふだん使っている布団に
女子高生を寝かせるというのは
抵抗があるわ
うん これは しかたない
Yes, there's no choice. Hanekawa-san, let's sleep together in my futon.
羽川さん
私の布団で一緒に寝ましょう
It's all right. Rest assured I won't do anything.
（戦場ヶ原）大丈夫 大丈夫 大丈夫
安心して　絶対 何もしないから
We're just sleeping in the same futon. I won't lay a finger on you.
同じ布団で寝るだけ
指１本 触れないから
I think I'm understanding why you're able to date Araragi-kun.
あなたが阿良々木くんと
つきあえる理由が分かった気がする
Animation Number 174
Hanekawa, I swear I won't use you as a body pillow!
All right, I get it. Say no more. That wasn't a concern.
いいよ　分かった 分かった
言われなくとも
そんな心配してないって
（戦場ヶ原）そう？　ありがとう
Really? Thank you.
Then you can use my pillow. I'll use my father's.
じゃあ 羽川さん
枕は 私のを使ってちょうだい
私は お父さんの枕を使うわ
What about the option of you sleeping in your father's futon?
（羽川）
戦場ヶ原さんがお父さんの布団を
使うという選択肢は ないの？
If I were to sleep in his futon, I wouldn't be able to sleep with you.
（戦場ヶ原）
だって 私が
お父さんの布団を使ったら
羽川さんと一緒に
寝られないじゃない
I see.
なるほど
Besides, I have an Electra complex, so I'd get too excited to sleep if I slept in his futon.
（戦場ヶ原）
それに 私って
実はファザコンだから
お父さんの布団で寝たりすると
興奮して
眠れなくなっちゃうのよね
Senjougahara-san, you're being too frank.
（羽川）
戦場ヶ原さん 赤裸々すぎる
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Well then, let's go to sleep, Down-filled Futon...
さあ それじゃあ 寝ましょうか
羽毛布団…
Animation Number 190
No, Hanekawa-san.
いえ 羽川さん
Down-filled Futon
Hanekawa
Animation Number 192
Nobody would ever say "down-filled futon" when thinking about saying "Hanekawa."
（羽川）“羽川”と言おうとして
“羽毛布団”とは
絶対に言わないよね
Good night.
（戦場ヶ原）おやすみなさい
（羽川）おやすみなさい
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It'd been so long since I said good night that it felt like it was my first time.
（羽川）
“おやすみなさい”と言ったのも
相当 久しぶりで
気分的には
初めてみたいなものだった
Tamikura-sou
Hoshinomiya
2-4-101
Let's climb
the stairs
quietly
Let's climb
the stairs
quietly
When dealing with a Roomba, you might say good morning, but you'd never say good night.
ルンバが相手では
おはようを言うことは あっても
おやすみを言うことは ないからね
Animation Number 199
1:30 PM, huh?
（戦場ヶ原）
午後１時半か
Animation Number 199
It feels like we really slept well. Did you wake up just now too?
結構 がっつり寝た感じね
羽川さんも 今 起きたところ？
Yeah, basically.
（羽川）うん そんな感じ
ウフ まさか 羽川さんと
I never thought we'd wake up in the same futon.
同じ布団で目を覚ますことが
あるなんてね
Don't make it sound like pillow talk.
（羽川）
ピロートークっぽいことを
言わないで
I'm high-strung, so I'm usually a light sleeper, but somehow I slept really deeply.
私 神経質だから
普段 眠りは浅いほうなんだけれど
なんだか ぐっすり眠れたわ
どうかしら？
これは 枕がよかったのかしら？
I wonder why? Maybe because I had a good pillow?
In any case, aren't you hungry?
さてと
羽川さん おなか すかない？
I was thinking about making some breakfast... no, lunch.
朝ご飯… じゃないわね
お昼ご飯でも
作ろうと思うんだけれど
Oh, sounds good. I'll definitely partake.
（羽川）
あっ いいね
ご相伴にあずかります
Do you have food you dislike?
（戦場ヶ原）
苦手な食べ物ってある？
No.
（羽川）ありません
（戦場ヶ原）そう
Okay. Lun-lun-lun...
（戦場ヶ原）るん るん るん
By the way, the kanji for "mo" in "moyashi" is the same "mo" in "moe."
ところで 羽川さん
もやしって漢字で書くと
“萌(も)やし”になるのよ
Animation Number 201
Moyashi
Ever since I learned that, they've been so good. So good.
それを知って以来 もやしが
おいしくて おいしくて
しかたがなくなったわ
Hopelessly good.
Well, knowing that didn't change its taste for me.
いや 私は それで
味が変わったりはしなかったけれど
So what do you think? Maybe calling someone a "beansprout kid" is actually a compliment.
となると どう？
もやしっ子って 実は すごい
褒め言葉なんじゃなくって？
Beansprout
Animation Number 208
Do you cook at all?
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さん 料理とかする人？
Yep, I do. Everything I eat I cook for myself.
（羽川）うん する
自分が食べるものは
全部 自分で作っていたわ
I see. I did that for a while too.
（戦場ヶ原）
そう　私にも そういう時期が
あったは あったわね
Thank you for this meal.
（戦場ヶ原）いただきます
（羽川）いただきます
Oh, it's good.
あっ おいし
（戦場ヶ原）あら そう？
Really? Araragi-kun wasn't thrilled with it, so I was honestly prepared for scathing criticism.
阿良々木くんには
あまり喜んでもらえなかったから
正直 酷評も
覚悟していたのだけれど…
（羽川）酷評って…
Scathing criticism? I think it's pretty good, but taste buds differ from person to person.
私は おいしいと思うけど
まあ 味覚って 個人差あるからね
In other words, our tastes are pretty similar.
つまり 私と羽川さんの好みは
似通っているということね
Our taste in food and in men.
味の好みも 男の好みも
Animation Number 235
Oh my, how bad-mannered of me
Senjougahara-san, you're really too frank about things like that.
戦場ヶ原さん
だから あなたは
そういうことに赤裸々すぎ
（戦場ヶ原）いえ まあ
Well, I thought it'd be better to discuss those things too so we could truly break the ice.
こういう話も していったほうが
いいのかなって思って
羽川さんと
本当に打ち解けるためには
One wrong step and the gap between us might have grown.
（羽川）
ひとつ間違ったら
溝が深まりそうだけれど
Animation Number 238
She's such a challenger
Then why don't we go out on a limb and tell each other what parts of Araragi-kun we like?
じゃあ 戦場ヶ原さん
いっそ思い切って お互いに
阿良々木くんの
どこが好きかって話でもする？
No, we shouldn't, because on the odd chance this leaks out, he'll go on an ego trip.
（戦場ヶ原）
いえ その思い切り方は
万一 この会話が外に漏れたときに
ヤツが調子に乗りかねないから
しないほうがいいわ
Then what should we discuss?
（羽川）じゃあ 何の話をする？
Let's see... Why don't we talk about what parts of him we detest.
（戦場ヶ原）そうね
阿良々木くんの どこが嫌いか
という話をしましょう
I'll take it.
乗った！
Animation Number 246
I think it's time we talk about the future.
（戦場ヶ原）
そろそろ 今後の話をしましょうか
羽川さん
What do you mean?
（羽川）今後の話というと？
I mean your future.
（戦場ヶ原）
だから 羽川さんの今後よ
今晩は 私の家に
泊まってもらうとして
Let's say you stay here tonight. What about tomorrow?
明日から どうする？
何か 当てはあるのかしら？
Do you have any ideas?
Ideas?
当ては…
None.
ない
I see.
そう
To be honest, I'd like you to stay over tomorrow and beyond as well...
本音を言えば 明日以降も
泊まっていってほしいんだけれど
But as you can tell, our home is cramped, so I can't possibly ask you,
でも 戦場ヶ原家は
見てのとおりの手狭さだから
さすがに 羽川さんに
明日 帰ってくる
お父さんと同じ部屋で
to sleep, wake up, and change in the same room as my father, who's back tomorrow.
寝起き お着替え
してもらうわけにはいかないわよね
Yeah, that would actually be a bit much.
（羽川）うん　確かに それは…
So what's your guess on the Hanekawa household's future?
（戦場ヶ原）
ちなみに 羽川さんの読みでは
羽川家の今後って どうなるの？
They'll get money from fire insurance, and while they're rebuilding
（羽川）火災保険が下りるから
そのお金で 家を建て直している間
借家で生活することに
なるでしょうね
I figure we'll be renting.
If your family hurries and finds a place to rent, at least that secures you a place to sleep, right?
取り急ぎ 借家先が決まれば
羽川さんの寝泊まりできる場所は
確保できるわけよね？
Well, then,
Standby
（戦場ヶ原）そう じゃあ
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hanekawa-san, I have a good idea. Want to hear it?
羽川さん いいアイデアが
あるんだけれど 聞きたい？
A good idea?
いいアイデア？
It should take your parents a week at most to find a place to rent.
（戦場ヶ原）
ご両親が借家先を決めるまで
かかっても
１週間というところでしょう
それくらいの間なら
まあ なんとかできると思うの
I think you could manage that with this idea.
I'd like to hear it. Please tell me.
うん 聞きたい　ぜひ聞かせて
Now what should I do? Should I tell you, or should I keep it to myself?
さあ どうしようかな？
言おうかな？
言わないでおこうかな？
Senjougahara-san turned a new leaf, and her candid personality became slightly more annoying.
（羽川）
更生して 淡泊だった性格が
若干ウザくなった
戦場ヶ原さんだった
Animation Number 269
（ブラック羽川）う〜ん うにゃっ
Nya!
There's no need to explain, as you've purrobably realized
（ブラック羽川）
説明するまでもにゃく
もう分かったと思うが
ご主人 つまり 羽川翼(つばさ)が寝たときに
章が飛んでいるのは
the chapter numbers skip when my myaster, Hanekawa Tsubasa, is asleep because I've come out.
こうやって
俺が登場していたからにゃ
The fact that the house she lived in for 15 years burned to the ground
15年間 暮らした家が
全焼してしまったというのは
caused a catastrophic shock to my myaster's spirit, or what you'd call her heart.
すさまじい衝撃を
ご主人の精神…
換言するところの心に
与えてしまったのにゃ
That's why I'm out.
だから 俺が出てきた
Animation Number 294
I've been making appurrances
Black Hanekawa's third appearance, meow.
ブラック羽川 三度(みたび)登場にゃ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I'm the incarnation of my myaster's stress, a symbol of fatigue.
俺は ご主人の
ストレスの権化であり
つまり 疲れの象徴であり
The mere fact that I'm cut off from my myaster like this gives her peace of mind.
こうして 俺が
切り離(はにゃ)されるだけで
ご主人本人にとっては
Animation Number 295
At least for my myaster. I've never purr a second hated her.
それが
安らぎににゃるにゃ
Animation Number 295
Not purr a second.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
にゃん にゃん
Maybe this way?
こっちかにゃん？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
No, purrobably this way.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
いや こっちかにゃん？
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
There it is.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
いたにゃ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Animation Number 312
Meddlecat. No, not quite...
（虎）障(さわ)り猫(ねこ)… いや 違う
You're not a Meddlecat. Even though I say that, you cannot be anything else.
障り猫ではない
かといって ほかの何でもない
What are you? You are what?
何だ？　お前は
お前は何だ？
Basically a Meddlecat.
障り猫で まあ 合ってるにゃん
正確には 細部が違うけれど
根本も違うけれど
To be purrecise, you got the details and fundamental concept wrong, but it's not too far off.
まあ そんにゃに
違うわけでもにゃい
Really? It seems like I'm completely off.
（虎）
そうか？
全然 違うように思うがな
The Meddlecat aberration I know is very weak, and you wouldn't know if it's there or not.
我が輩の知る
障り猫という怪異は 貧弱で
いるかいないか 分からないような
存在感のない怪異だ
But you...
しかし お前は…
Putting it that way, I can't say much.
まあ そう言われると
一言(いちごん)もにゃいにゃん
Animation Number 332
Can't argue with that
Stuff happens, even for things like me.
いろいろ あるんだよ
俺みたいにゃヤツにも
Animation Number 332
Meddlecats
that maybe we're rather just odd stories, not oddities.
I see. Well, I couldn't care less about you.
（虎）そうか
まあ お前のことなんか
どうでもいい
But I must ask what you want of me.
しかし 何の用かは
聞かねばならんな
As the same type of aberration, you must know what it means to bar my path.
我が輩の行く手を遮る意味を
同種の怪異たるお前が
分からんはずもなかろうに
The same type?
同種の怪異？
I should be a completely different type of aberration from this guy.
（ブラック羽川）
俺と こいつとじゃ
怪異としての出自は
全然 違うはずにゃんだが
Animation Number 340
A cat and a tiger—he must mean
we're similar in that way
I really don't intend to get in your way, meow.
（ブラック羽川）
別に お前の行く手を
遮ろうというつもりは
俺には にゃい
（虎）
では お前は
どうして そこに立っている？
Then why do you stand there?
Well, just to warn you.
（ブラック羽川）
いや 単に 宣言しに来ただけにゃ
I couldn't care less what your businyess in this town is.
お前が どういうつもりで
この町に来たのか
俺は 全く興味がにゃい
And I don't care what your duties are.
お前の本分が何(にゃん)にゃのかも
俺にとっては
どうでもいいことにゃん
That's how aberrations are.
怪異ってのは
そういうもんにゃんだからよ
But if you happen to cause any more harm to my myaster,
だが もしも
もしも これ以上
お前が 俺のご主人に
害をにゃすようにゃことがあれば
I will kill you.
俺は お前を殺す
I see. I thought I recognized you from somewhere.
（虎）そうか
どこかで見覚えがあると思ったが
お前 あの娘か
You're that girl. You've possessed that girl.
Under construction
Sorry for the inconvenience
あの娘に取りついているのか
That's inyaccurate. I haven't possessed her.
取りついているわけじゃ
にゃいにゃん
If I was a decent Meddlecat, that'd be the case. But I'm more like the girl herself.
まっとうにゃ障り猫にゃら
そうにゃんだろうけどにゃ
俺は 本人みたいにゃもんにゃ
I don't care either way.
（虎）ふん どうでもいい
An aberration that sides with humans. That's not all that uncommon.
人間に肩入れする怪異か
珍しくもない
だが お前のような怪異こそが
いちばん よく分かっているだろう
However, aberrations like you know best.
You can't hold back the traits of aberrations. The problem lies in those that can see them.
怪異の特性というものは
抑えられるものではない
見たほうの問題だ
Animation Number 353
The one you call your "master" saw me.
お前のご主人とやらが
我が輩を見た
That's all that matters.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
重要なのは それだけだ
School
It's useless.
（虎）ムダだ
It's all useless.
全ては ムダだ
その女… あの女は 我が輩を見た
The girl... That girl saw me.
それだけが肝要で
That alone is essential. That alone is important.
それだけが重要だ
I have already started acting.
我が輩は もう 始まっている
Animation Number 380
Can you wipe your feet before coming in?
部屋に入る前に
足を拭いてくれる？
I'm a light sleeper since I'm high-strung. Didn't I tell you that?
寝起きは いいほうなのよ
神経質だから
そう言わなかったっけ？
It's not like you told me, meow.
（ブラック羽川）
俺が言われたわけじゃ
にゃいにゃん
But you're still Hanekawa-san, right?
（戦場ヶ原）
でも あなた
羽川さんなんでしょう？
Though this is the first time I'm meeting you. Is Black Hanekawa-san all right?
あなたと会ったのは
初めてだけれど
ブラック羽川さんで
いいんだっけ？
Well, something like that.
まっ そんにゃところにゃ
I see.
そう
What are you trying to do, meow?
（ブラック羽川）
ん？　何のつもりにゃ？
I thought we'd shake hands in salutation.
（戦場ヶ原）
はじめましての握手を
しようと思って
Haven't you heard a thing?
（ブラック羽川）
お前 何(にゃに)も聞いてにゃいのか？
My special ability as a Meddlecat is purrpetual Energy Drain.
障り猫としての俺の特性は
常時発動型のエニャジードレイン
By merely touching someone, I drain their life force.
触ったら それだけで
相手の精力を吸い上げてしまう
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
A handshake's out of the question.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
握手にゃんて
とんでもにゃいにゃん
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Energy Drain. I've heard of that, but it's not like you'll drain it all in an instant, right?
エニャジードレイン
それは聞いているけれど
でも 一瞬で全てを
吸い取るわけじゃないでしょう？
I'm sure you can at least manage a handshake.
握手くらい できるはずよ
Nice to meet you.
よろしくね
Take good care of Hanekawa-san for me.
羽川さんのこと よろしく
Animation Number 407
Why? We skipped three whole chapters now.
（羽川）
なぜだろう？
Animation Number 407
今度は一気に
３章も飛んでいる
Animation Number 407
Something must have happened while I was asleep.
私が寝ている間に
何があったのだ？
Animation Number 407
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Good morning, Hanekawa-san.
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（戦場ヶ原）
おはよう 羽川さん
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
You're an early riser. It's still 6 AM.
羽川さん 朝 早いのね
まだ６時よ
Yeah. But you're awake too, Senjougahara-san.
うん　でも 戦場ヶ原さんも
起きてるじゃない
I go on a short jog in the mornings.
私は 朝は軽く走るから
このスタイルを維持するために
これでも結構 苦労しているのよ
I go through a lot of hard work to keep this figure.
I'm the type that easily stores anything I eat as blubber.
食べたものが
肉になりやすい体質なの 私って
Animation Number 420
You seem tired
Would you like to jog with me?
羽川さんも 一緒に走る？
Animation Number 421
I like to run when I'm tired
No thanks. I'll just make some breakfast while you're out jogging, Senjougahara-san.
（羽川）いえ　じゃあ 私は
戦場ヶ原さんが走ってる間に
朝食を作らせてもらうわ
Let's eat together when you're back.
帰ってきたら 一緒に食べましょ
Animation Number 423
Oh, that looks good.
あら おいしそう
Do you have a moment, Hanekawa-san?
羽川さん ちょっといいかしら？
What is it?
何でしょう？
No, hold on. First...
（戦場ヶ原）あっ いえ 待って
とりあえず この…
About this unbelievable situation...
信じられない事態に
I have to be sure.
確信を持つわ
Huh, did I screw up something?
（羽川）
あれ？　何か失敗したかな？
Hmm...
（戦場ヶ原）ふ〜む
Senjougahara-san...
（羽川）あの 戦場ヶ原さん
Hanekawa-san, do you know about salad dressing?
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さん
ドレッシングって知ってる？
Huh?
Chinese
dressing
Tare sauce
Of course I know. You mean the stuff that's poured on salads occasionally?
そりゃ もちろん知ってるけど
たまに サラダにかかっている
あれだよね？
I see. I see.
なるほど なるほど
Of the three fried-egg factions,
目玉焼きに ソースをかける派と
しょうゆをかける派
what do you think of those who use pepper, chuno sauce, or soy sauce?
あるいは コショウをかける派の
三つどもえの争いについて
どう思う？
Pepper
Chuno sauce
Oh, I heard rumors of people putting stuff on their fried eggs.
（羽川）
ああ　ウワサでは いるらしいね
目玉焼きに何かかける人って
Yup, yup.
Did you realize we had butter and jam in the fridge?
バターとかジャムとかが
冷蔵庫に入っていたの気付いてた？
I saw them.
あったけど
You put them out for me yesterday. Oh, sorry. Did you want them?
昨日 出してもらったし
あっ ごめん
ひょっとして使った？
A few more questions.
（戦場ヶ原）更に いくつか質問
（羽川）どうぞ どうぞ
Go ahead.
（戦場ヶ原）
羽川さんの食生活についてね
About your eating habits.
My eating habits? I think my eating habits are very ordinary.
（羽川）私の食生活？
私の食生活なんて
とても平凡なものだと思うけれど
Animation Number 458
The
questioning
begins
Soy sauce for sushi?
おすしに しょうゆは？
I don't dip.
つけない
Tsuyu for tempura?
天ぷらに つゆは？
I don't dip.
つけない
Sugar in yogurt?
ヨーグルトにグラニュー糖を？
I don't put any.
（羽川）入れない
Ketchup letters on hamburg steaks or omelets?
ハンバーグやオムレツに
ケチャップで文字を？
I don't write any.
書かない
Sauce on okonomiyaki?
お好み焼きにソースは？
I don't brush any.
塗らない
Salt in onigiri?
お握りに塩は？
Not mixed in.
混ぜない
How much sugar in your coffee after a meal?
食後のコーヒー
お砂糖は おいくつ？
Black please.
ブラックでお願いします
Okay.
Animation Number 472
The
questioning
ends
（戦場ヶ原）
はい
Oh, I get it now. I'm sorry. Senjougahara-san, you're the type that uses salad dressing.
（羽川）
ああ 分かった 分かった
ごめんなさい
戦場ヶ原さんは ドレッシングを
かける派だったんだね
That's why you were making that strange face.
だから あんなふうに
おかしな顔をしていたんだ
No. I wasn't aware that people who didn't use dressing existed until now.
いえ 私は
ドレッシングをかけない派の存在を
今まで認識していなかったのよ
I've never seen anyone eat fried eggs plain and put out plain bread.
プレーンな目玉焼きというのも
初めて見たし
パンがパンのまま
ごろっと出てきたのも初めてだわ
Are you one of those people vehemently opposed to seasoning?
羽川さんって あれ？
料理の味付けに対し
拒絶的な人なの？
The type that enjoys the ingredients' natural flavors?
素材の味を
そのまま堪能したいとか？
It's not that.
そういうわけじゃ ないわよ
But isn't food good even without flavor?
でも 料理って
味がなくても おいしいじゃない
There's the comment that seals the deal.
（戦場ヶ原）
決め手となる発言が登場したわ
I'm just saying it's the same whether it has flavor or not.
（羽川）え？　私は ただ
味は あっても なくても
一緒だって言ってるだけだよ？
They say secrets don't come from questioning, but slips of the tongue.
問うに落ちず 語るに落ちるとは
このことだわ
Animation Number 486
The cat's been out of the bag for quite a while now.
Thank you for that meal.
ごちそうさまでした
I completely take back my assertion that our tastes in food are similar.
（戦場ヶ原）
あなたと味の好みが
似ているという話は
全面的に取り消すわ
You're like the polar opposite of a picky eater. Not that you have no preferences either.
（戦場ヶ原）
偏食の逆みたいな人なのね
羽川さん
好き嫌いがないというのとも
違うわ
I'm sorry, Senjougahara-san. I still don't really understand what you're saying.
（羽川）ごめん 戦場ヶ原さん
私 いまだに 何を言われてるか
よく分からないんだけれど
A taste of home, huh?
家庭の味… ね
That's not it either. I guess it just means you accept any flavoring, Hanekawa-san.
でも そういうわけじゃなくって
羽川さんは どんな味でも
受け入れてしまうって
ことなのかしらね
In the extreme, I'd say you just need it to be edible and nutritious.
極端に言えば
食べられて 栄養を取れれば
それでいいっていうか
Or just filling if it's not nutritious?
いや 栄養が取れなくとも
腹に たまればいいのかしら？
Don't make me out to be some warrior!
人をそんな
戦士みたいに言わないでよ
That you can taste is a burden. If you're not enjoying each ingredient's flavor
（戦場ヶ原）
味が分かる分 やっかいよね
素材の味を楽しんでるってわけでも
ないというのなら
結局は 器が大きいってことに
なるのかしら？
I guess it ends up being that you have a big heart.
But I think something's wrong with living like that, Hanekawa-san.
でもね 羽川さん
そういう生き方って
どうかとは思うわよ
It's not something limited to your eating habits. You always, you know,
食生活に限ったことじゃなくて
あなたって こう…
accept anything and everything as it comes your way.
何でもかんでも
受け入れちゃうじゃない？
To have something you detest is about as important as having something you love.
嫌いなものがあるっていうのは
好きなものがあるのと同じくらい
大切なことじゃない
Yet you accept everything that comes your way, right?
それなのに あなたは
何でもかんでも
受け入れちゃうじゃない？
That may be the case with me, and that may also be the case with Araragi-kun.
私のことも
そうなのかもしれないし
阿良々木くんのことも
そうなのかもしれない
At least that's what I think.
なんて思うんだけれど
Animation Number 509
Did we change the subject?
Did we stray from the subject?
Animation Number 509
Did the subject get much wider?
No, that's not it.
It's not that we shared tastes in food.
（戦場ヶ原）
味の好みは
似通っているのではなく
It was merely that your tastes in food completely enveloped my tastes.
私の好みを 羽川さんの好みが
包み込んでいる
というだけのことだったのね
No, I don't think I can call your preferences "tastes."
いえ 羽川さんのは
好みとは言えないかもしれないわ
Animation Number 511
Some things are better left unsaid.
Because if you like anything and everything, they all end up being the same thing in the end.
だって 何でもどれでも
好きなんじゃ
どれも同じみたいなものだものね
Animation Number 514
Hanekawa-san?
ねえ 羽川さん
Purple Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Senjougahara-san continued without looking away from my eyes.
（羽川）
戦場ヶ原さんが
私の目を見つめたままで言う
Were you really in love with Araragi-kun?
（戦場ヶ原）
あなた 本当に阿良々木くんのこと
好きだったの？
She sounded a little like she once did, with a flat tone of voice.
（羽川）
それは 少しだけ
昔みたいな平たんな口調だった
Can you tell me once more that you're still in love with Araragi-kun?
今でも阿良々木くんが好きだって
もっかい言える？
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
I'm Tsukihi!
And Tsukihi!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
White Cat
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
（月火･火憐）
２人合わせて
“ファイヤーシスターズ”！
While the two of us form the Fire Sisters, what if a third member were to join in?
Night Patrol!
Time to Strike
（月火）
２人合わせただけでも
ファイヤーシスターズなのに
これが ３人合わせたら
もう どうなっちゃうことか！
Well there is no such third member to begin with.
（火憐）
３人目なんか いないけどな
Now the Preview Quiz you haven't been waiting for!
（月火）
お待ちかね 予告編クイズ！
I'll Surprise them!
Pretending to go to sleep
under the stars
That should be "have been". "Have been".
（火憐）
お待ちかねって言うほど
お待ちかねえ？
There are some living things like us Fire Sisters that are a ten out of ten, however...
（月火）
１足す１を５にも10にもするのが
私たちファイヤーシスターズですが
（火憐）
ですが？
However?
Ah! Found the Cat!
Success
There are also things living in this world that are rated zero.
（月火）
１足す１がゼロになっちゃうことも
世の中 ままありますよね
Similarly, despite all the wonderful things one could come across, there are things with zero selling point whatsoever.
すばらしいものと
すばらしいものを足したのに
なぜか 互いに
いいところを潰し合っちゃうという
Gahara-san!
Found You!
Meow?
Oh? Like what?
（火憐）
ほうほう　例えば？
A tea cup made of mahogany.
（月火）
マホガニーのティーカップ
（火憐）
ゼロになった
Zero indeed!
（月火）
エスプレッソのベンティサイズ
An expresso-sized panty.
Absolute zero!
（火憐）
ゼロすぎる！
Next Time
Tsubasa Tiger Part 3
Next time! Nekomonogatari Shiro Episode 3!
（火憐･月火）
次回「猫物語（白）」
第３話「つばさタイガー其ノ参(そのさん)」
Tsubasa Tiger, Part 3.
Nadeko-chan and I.
Sorry!
You're a girl!
You can't spend the night out there alone!
She's got a girl's body.
She got used to being touched.
（月火）
撫子(なでこ)ちゃんに 私
That makes you minus 1.
（火憐）
それは 月火ちゃんが
マイナス１なんじゃ…